In the 2024.2 version, Cloud's component simulation has been improved, and the component will be affected by gravity and the interaction force of the panels.
These improvements also make the display effect of the component more realistic. At the same time, the stability of the component simulation has also been greatly improved.
We will show the functions after the improvement through the component on this suit.
First, we insert a component into the object window and attach it to the panel with a glue stick, then adjust its position.
When you use the right-click unit component, you can see that the simulation option has been increased in the right-click menu, and the state of the component simulation is also divided into freeze, activate, and counter-activate.
Since the glue tool is used at this time, you can see that the component simulation has been improved.
The left-click unit component is unable to switch to freeze or activate.
When you use the right-click unit component to remove the glue, the three simulation states can be switched at this time.
Select the activation option and start simulation.
After running the simulation, use the grab to drag the component, you can see that it is presented under the state of gravity and the interaction force of the panel.
The component will fall down a little due to gravity, and the interaction force between the panel and the panel will be hung by the panel.
The effect of the real component and the panel are the same.
And the right-click component editor has also been added to the simulation of the conflict thickness and rigidity.
You can adjust the conflict thickness between the component and the panel by entering the value.
In the previous version, the component that did not use the glue tool glue after running the simulation will not be affected by gravity.
Therefore, it will remain in the original position and will not fall down in the direction of gravity.
In the component simulation, the connection is frozen, and it can be fixed to the component as in the previous version.
Let's switch to the other component.
Right-click the component, choose to freeze, and start simulation.
The component will not fall down under gravity.
Using the grab to move the component, you can see that the interaction force between the component and the panel also exists.
Unlike the activation, after the component is frozen, you can see that the rigidity in the right attribute editor window is gray.
This is because after the component is frozen, there will be no deformation.
Therefore, the rigidity of the component cannot be changed.
According to the difference in the component type, in the 2024.2 version, the component will be transformed by the interaction force between the component and the panel.
First, the component must also be in the state of activation.
Activate the component, check whether the rigidity simulated in the right attribute editor is used.
Rigidity refers to the degree of rigidity of the component.
The default rigidity of the component is 50,000.
The minimum value is 5000.
The maximum value can be entered to 100,000.
Then, when we reduce the rigidity of the component to 50,000.
Turn on simulation.
You can see that the component is more likely to be pulled by the power of the panel, transform.
On the other hand, if you want to set it as a solid component that is not easy to transform, you can increase its rigidity.
You can adjust its rigidity according to the real effect of the component.
Finally, right-click the component, select the reverse activation simulation.
Turn on simulation.
The component is kept in its original position.
Use your hand to grab the component.
You can see the interaction between the component and the panel.
and the interaction effect of the 3D window has also disappeared.
From this version,
the add-on in the 3D window that does not use the glue stick attached to the board
can also show the effect of the add-on in the gravity function.
We first right-click the add-on and select Activate.
Then select the add-on in the object window.
Find the option of Weight at the bottom of the attribute editor.
At this time, the weight of the add-on is 7.6 grams.
Simulate to check the effect of the add-on under the current weight.
Then change the weight of the add-on to 50 grams,
and then simulate.
You can find that the add-on is more in the gravity function.
The above is the new function of our add-on simulation.
It should be noted that the current add-on simulation is only suitable for CPU simulation.
Based on this,
you can set the hardness or weight of the add-on according to the type of add-on you want,
and adjust it to make the display effect of the add-on simulation more realistic.
END
BEFORE
AFTER